A Guide to the Robert Young Clay Papers, 1789-2010 (bulk 1920-2007)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Robert Young Clay Papers, 1789-2010 (bulk 1920-2007)
The Library of Virginia
45033
74.5 cubic feet (171 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Estate of Robert Young Clay, Dinwiddie.
Biographical Information
Robert Young Clay was born in Dixon Springs, Smith County, Tennessee on 4 September 1936. He was the son of Robert Bell Clay (1888-1957) and Ruth Young (1906-1951). He received a Bachelor of Fine Arts degree from the University of Tennessee in 1960, and a Master of Library Science degree from George Peabody College in 1969. Clay moved to Richmond the following year, where he was employed as a reference archivist at the Library of Virginia until his retirement in 2001. He also had a career as a landscape painter and heraldic artist. Clay died in Richmond on 6 May 2010, and is buried in the Clay family plot in Dixon Springs Cemetery.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1789-2010, of Robert Young Clay (1936-2010) of Richmond, Virginia, including his research on the Clay family and allied lines, subject files, speeches, pension records of soldiers from Smith County, Tennessee, and artwork. The bulk of the collection covers the period 1920 to 2007.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in the following five series:
I. Clay Family Research Files (Subseries a-j).
II. Subject Files.
III. Speech Files.
IV. Smith County, TN Soldiers' Pension Files.
V. Artwork.
Contents List
- Series I. Clay Family Research Files., Extent: 97 boxes. (Box 1-97)
  The Clay Family Research Files are divided into ten subseries, including: a) Alphabetical Files. b) Locality Files. c) Subject Files. d) Clay Family Society Records. e) Ballow, Escue, Kittrell, and Young Family Research Files. f) Allied Families (A-Z). g) Notebooks. h) Photographs. i) Card Files. j) Microfilm. The series documents Clay's interest in tracing the descendants of John Clay, and more specifically those of Thomas Clay (1745/6-1812) of Dinwiddie County, Virginia.
  - Subseries A. Alphabetical Files., Extent: 15 boxes. (Box 1-14)
    The Alphabetical Files contain information that was used to compile data sheets on specific individuals. There are copies, abstracts, and transcriptions of census records, county court records, land office records, vital statistics, and tax records. There is also information Clay received from other researchers, correspondence, obituaries, Bible records, pedigrees and genealogical charts, published sources, pension records, and tombstone inscriptions.
    - Clay, Abia 13525. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Clay, Abner. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Clay, Absolom. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Clay, Albert G. - Russell County, VA. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Clay, Allen (Cousin George M. Clay's son). (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Clay, Allen - Documentation. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Clay, Allen - Granville County, NC. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Clay, Anderson T.. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Clay, Andrew J. - C.S.A.. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Clay, Archer. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Clay, Arthur Stevenson. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Clay, Aubrey S.. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Clay, Avarilla. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Clay, Britain. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Clay, Caleb. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Clay, Carlos Green. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Clay, Carr. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Clay, Cassius Marcellus. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Clay, Charles. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Clay, Charles m. Amy Wilson Eppes. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Clay, Charles 1353. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Clay, Charles 13522. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Clay, Rev. Charles 13533. (Box 1, Folder 23-24)
    - Clay, Rev. Charles 13533. (Box 171, Folder 1)
    - Clay, Charles 136. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Clay, Charles 1362?. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Clay, Charles - Amelia County, VA. (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
    - Clay, Charles - Dinwiddie County, VA 13645. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Clay, Charles - Halifax County, VA. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Clay, Charles - Halifax County, VA - Land Entries. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Clay, Charles - Henrico County, VA. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Clay, Charles - Henrico County, VA (Signature). (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Clay, Charles - Mecklenburg County, VA. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Clay, Charles - Nottoway County, VA. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Clay, Charles Sr.. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Clay, Charles Clement. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Clay, Charles Edward. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Clay, Charles M. - Civil War Pension. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Clay, Charles W. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Clay, Charlotte. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Clay, Clement C.. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Clay, Cleopatra. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Clay, Courtney Mallory. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Clay, Daniel 13415. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Clay, Daniel - Amelia County, VA. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Clay, Daniel - Halifax County, VA - Descendants. (Box 2, Folder 22-24)
    - Clay, Daniel Jr. 13637 5. (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Clay, Daniel W.. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Clay, David. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Clay, David - Amelia County, VA. (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Clay, David - Georgia. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Clay, David A.. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Clay, Delphia W.. (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Clay, Delphy - Amelia County, VA. (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Clay, Earl Taft. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Clay, Edward 13542. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Clay, Edward - Dinwiddie County, VA. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Clay, Edward - Nottoway County, VA. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Clay, Edward Lee Sr.. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Clay, Edward T. - Nottoway County, VA. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Clay, Elijah. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Clay, Elijah 1352x. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Clay, Elijah S. - Pendleton and Grant Counties, KY. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Clay, Elijah - Revolutionary War NC. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Clay, Elizabeth. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Clay, Elizabeth Hudson. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Clay, Emmett Stratton - C.S.A.. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Clay, Evans P.. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Clay, Ezekiel - Franklin County, VA. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Clay, Ezekiel - Montgomery County, VA. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Clay, Fanny. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Clay, Frances - Lewisburg, WV. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Clay, Frank Benjamin (Altavista). (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Clay, Frederick. (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Clay, Frederick - Halifax County, VA. (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Clay, George - Halifax County, VA. (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Clay, George Ambrose. (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Clay, George H. - Russell County, VA. (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Clay, Giles Logan. (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Clay, Green 13539. (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Clay, Green - Arkansas. (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Clay, Green Gable - C.S.A.. (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Clay, Hannah m. Matthew Cabaniss. (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Clay, Hannah m. Richard Cureton. (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Clay, Harriet Coleman. (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Clay, Henry. (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Clay, Henry (d. 1764). (Box 170, Folder 3)
    - Clay, Henry 135. (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Clay, Henry 1352. (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Clay, Henry 13521. (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Clay, Henry 13534. (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Clay, Henry - Senator 13541 5. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Clay, Henry - Albemarle County, NC (Headright). (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Clay, Henry - Amelia County, VA. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Clay, Henry - Dinwiddie County, VA. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Clay, Henry - Final Suit and Settlement. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Clay, Henry - Henrico County, VA. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Clay, Henry - Mecklenburg County, VA. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Clay, Henry - North Carolina (ca. 1693/4). (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Clay, Henry - 7th Mississippi Infantry. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Clay, Henry M. - Halifax County, VA. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Clay, Henry Milton. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Clay, Henry R. - Richmond City. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Clay, Henry Watkins. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Clay, Henry Yancey. (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Clay, Hezekiah. (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Clay, India. (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Clay, Isham. (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Clay, Isham - Cabaruss County, NC. (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Clay, Isham of Tybee Light. (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Clay, J.E. - Pikeville, TN. (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Clay, J.W. - Pittsylvania County, VA. (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Clay, James. (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Clay, James 1342. (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Clay, James - Dinwiddie County, VA. (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Clay, James - Halifax County, VA. (Box 4, Folder 25-27)
    - Clay, James - Henrico County, VA. (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Clay, James - Smith County, TN. (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Clay, James - Warren County, MO. (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Clay, James C.. (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Clay, James D. - Halifax County, VA. (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Clay, James Dearing. (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Clay, James H. - Amelia County, VA. (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Clay, James L.. (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Clay, James Lee. (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Clay, James Louis - Ashland, KY. (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Clay, James M. - Lawrence County, KY/Giles County, VA. (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Clay, James S. - Williamson County, TN. (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Clay, James W. and Thomas Christian. (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Clay, Jennings J.. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Clay, Jeremiah. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Clay, Jeremiah Bass. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Clay, Jesse - Amelia County, VA 13415. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Clay, Jesse - Amelia County, VA 13633. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Clay, Jesse - Henry County, VA 13515. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Clay, Jesse - Jasper County, GA. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Clay, Jesse B.. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Clay, John. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Clay, John 1. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Clay, John - Prince George County, VA 133. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Clay, John 1343. (Box 5, Folder 12-13)
    - Clay, John 13431. (Box 5, Folder 14-15)
    - Clay, John 13512 7. (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Clay, John 1354. (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Clay, Sir John. (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Clay, Sir John 13541. (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Clay, John 13541 1. (Box 5, Folder 20-21)
    - Clay, John m. Millicent Epps. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Clay, John m. Patty Ingram. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Clay, John - Amelia County, VA. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Clay, John and Company - Amelia County, VA. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Clay, John - Amelia County, VA (Ordinary Keeper). (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Clay, John - Brunswick County, VA. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Clay, John - Charles City County Militia. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Clay, John - Chesterfield County, VA (re: Mill). (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Clay, John - Dinwiddie County, VA. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Clay, John - Franklin County, VA. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Clay, John - Grayson County, VA. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Clay, John - Mecklenburg County, VA. (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
    - Clay, John - North Carolina Revolutionary War Private. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Clay, John - York County, VA. (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Clay, John C. - Louisiana. (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Clay, John Gillem. (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Clay, Mrs. John Harris - Kentucky. (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Clay, John J. - Richmond, VA. (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Clay, John Matt. (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Clay, John Mitchell. (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Clay, John Moore. (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Clay, John T. - Halifax County, VA. (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Clay, John T. - Lawrenceville, VA. (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Clay, John T. - Fayette County, WV. (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Clay, John Thomas Green. (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Clay, John W. - Campbell County, VA. (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Clay, Mrs. Johnnie Massey - Bowling Green, KY. (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Clay, Joseph. (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Clay, Joseph - Dyer County, TN. (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Clay, Joseph - South Carolina. (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Clay, Joseph - Tennessee. (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Clay, Joseph W. m. Rebecca E.H. Vaughan. (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Clay, Joshua - Carroll County, VA. (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Clay, Josiah - Halifax County, VA. (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Clay, Josiah Thomas m. Lucy Jane Hillsman. (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Clay, Judith Ann - Amelia County, VA. (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Clay, L. Neal S. - Pittsylvania County, VA. (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Clay, Lacy F.. (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Clay, Larkin - Nottoway County, VA. (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Clay, Lemuel - Franklin County, VA. (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Clay, Leodora (Loda). (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Clay, Leonidas Hugh. (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Clay, Levi 13511 1. (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Clay, Gen. Lucius. (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Clay, Lucy (Marshall). (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Clay, Marston 13526. (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Clay, Marston - Henderson County, KY. (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Clay, Marstone. (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Clay, Marstone. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Clay, Marstone 13524 5. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Clay, Martha - Richmond, VA (Infant). (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Clay, Mary - Westminster (England?). (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Clay, Matthew 13538. (Box 7, Folder 5-8)
    - Clay, Meredith. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Clay, Middleton. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Clay, Mitchell 13514. (Box 7, Folder 11-15)
    - Clay, Munroe. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Clay, Nancy - Prince George County, VA (Petersburg). (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Clay, Nathan. (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Clay, Nestor. (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Clay, Obadiah (Obed). (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Clay, Odin Green 14533 2. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Clay, Olive. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Clay, Paul A.. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Clay, Paul C. - Inventory, 1874. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Clay, Paul C. - Inventory, 1874. (Box 170, Folder 4)
    - Clay, Paul Carrington. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Clay, Dr. Paul Carrington. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Clay, Dr. Paul - Compiled Descendants. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Clay, Percibal/Pierce - Georgia. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Clay, Peter. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Clay, Peter 13632. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Clay, Peter M.. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Clay, Phinehas. (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Clay, Physic Ridley. (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Clay, Pleasant. (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Clay, Porter. (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Clay, Reuben A.. (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Clay, Richard A.. (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Clay, Richard E. - Amelia County, VA. (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Clay, Robert. (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Clay, Robert - Lexington, KY. (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Clay, Robert Bell. (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Clay, Robert Carter (son of Melvin). (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Clay, Robert Hatcher. (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Clay, Robert Lee. (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Clay, Robert T.. (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Clay, Robert Young. (Box 9, Folder 1-4)
    - Clay, Robert Young - Pedigree Chart (Map-case 56, Drawer 5)
    - Clay, Royal. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Clay, Russell. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Clay, Salley 13418. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Clay, Salley and Tolbert - Mecklenburg County, VA. (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Clay, Samuel. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Clay, Samuel 13523. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Clay, Samuel - Richmond, VA. (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Clay, Samuel E. m. Grace Poe. (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Clay, Samuel M.. (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Clay, Samuel Mitchell. (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Clay, Samuel Paton. (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Clay, Samuel W. - Dinwiddie County, VA. (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Clay, Sarah - Amelia County, VA. (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Clay, Shadrick. (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Clay, Sidney Preston. (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Clay, Solomon - Clay County, TN. (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Clay, Solomon (NC to Perry County, MO). (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Clay, Stephen. (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Clay, Stephen - Will, 1734. (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Clay, Stephen - Compiled Descendants. (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Clay, Stonewall Jackson. (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Clay, Tabitha - Montgomery County, VA. (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Clay, Tacitus. (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Clay, Thomas 134. (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Clay, Thomas - Dinwiddie County, VA. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Clay, Thomas (Cousins vs. Hardaway). (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Clay, Thomas - Forms and Letters Out. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Clay, Thomas - Land in Dinwiddie. (Box 10, Folder 4-7)
    - Clay, Thomas - Petitions. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Clay, Thomas - Allied Families.
      - Butler. (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Christian. (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Christian, Anthony (Jr. and Sr.). (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Dearing. (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Herod. (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - Lynch. (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Nash. (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - Prosser. (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - Watkins. (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Clay, Thomas - Clippings.
      - Arthur. (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - Atkins. (Box 10, Folder 19)
      - Bailey. (Box 10, Folder 20)
      - Baker. (Box 10, Folder 21)
      - Bentley. (Box 10, Folder 22)
      - Berkley. (Box 10, Folder 23)
      - Boisseau. (Box 10, Folder 24)
      - Bond. (Box 10, Folder 25)
      - Booker. (Box 10, Folder 26)
      - Bryant. (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Cabaniss. (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Canada. (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Carter. (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Clark. (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Clowdis. (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Clay. (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Clay (TN Clippings). (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Cornwell. (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Donoho. (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Dotson. (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Elder. (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - Elliott. (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Foster. (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - Gann. (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - Harper. (Box 11, Folder 16)
      - Henderson. (Box 11, Folder 17)
      - Herod. (Box 11, Folder 18)
      - Holt. (Box 11, Folder 19)
      - Jones. (Box 11, Folder 20)
      - Joy. (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - Kemp. (Box 11, Folder 22)
      - Magann. (Box 11, Folder 23)
      - Mills. (Box 11, Folder 24)
      - Moore. (Box 11, Folder 25)
      - Overstreet. (Box 11, Folder 26)
      - Nash. (Box 11, Folder 27-28)
      - Parkhurst. (Box 11, Folder 29)
      - Pettit. (Box 11, Folder 30)
      - Phelps. (Box 11, Folder 31)
      - Pugh. (Box 11, Folder 32)
      - Ramsey. (Box 11, Folder 33)
      - Rooser. (Box 11, Folder 34)
      - St. John. (Box 11, Folder 35)
      - Snell. (Box 11, Folder 36)
      - Vassar. (Box 11, Folder 37)
      - Webb. (Box 11, Folder 38)
      - Wilburn. (Box 11, Folder 39)
      - Wood. (Box 11, Folder 40)
      - Woodall. (Box 11, Folder 41)
      - Woodard. (Box 11, Folder 42)
      - Younger. (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Clay, Thomas - Addresses. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Clay, Thomas - Bibles. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Clay, Thomas - Census. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Clay, Thomas - Correspondence. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Clay, Thomas - General Notes. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Clay, Thomas - Land. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Clay, Thomas - Slaves. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Clay, Thomas m. Ann Powell. (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Clay, Thomas - Son of Charles Clay and Martha Green. (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Clay, Thomas - Revolutionary War Artillery. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Clay, Thomas - Revolutionary War Pension. (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Clay, Thomas - Search For. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Clay, Thomas - Virginia State Line. (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Clay, Thomas - War of 1812 (m. Susan Smart). (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Clay, Thomas - Amelia County, VA (fl. 1822). (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Clay, Thomas - Amelia County, VA (Estray Notice). (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Clay, Thomas - Amelia County/Petersburg, VA. (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Clay, Thomas - Brunswick County, VA. (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Clay, Thomas - Halifax County, VA. (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Clay, Thomas - Pittsylvania County, VA. (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Clay, Thomas - Powhatan County, VA. (Box 12, Folder 21-22)
    - Clay, Thomas (Various). (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Clay, Thomas F. m. Ida Coleman. (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Clay, Thomas Green. (Box 12, Folder 25-26)
    - Clay, Dr. Thomas Green. (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
    - Clay, Thomas J. - Madison County, AL. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Clay, Thomas Newton. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Clay, Thomas Watkins. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Clay, Trace (Thomas Franklin). (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Clay, Virginia Caroline Tunstall. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Clay, Watkins. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Clay, William 11. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Clay, William 13512. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Clay, William 13512 6. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Clay, William 1363. (Box 13, Folder 12-13)
    - Clay, William m. Mary Ann Compton. (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Clay, William m. Ann Old. (Box 13, Folder 15-17)
    - Clay, William and Permelia. (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Clay, William (son of Mitchell). (Box 13, Folder 19-20)
    - Clay, William (Various). (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Clay, William - Franklin County, VA. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Clay, William - Halifax County, VA and TN - War of 1812 Pension. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Clay, William - Henry County, VA. (Box 14, Folder 2a)
    - Clay, William - Isle of Wight County, VA. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Clay, William - Nottoway County, VA. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Clay, William - South Carolina. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Clay, William - Tazewell County, VA. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Clay, William - Texas/Oklahoma. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Clay, William Carl. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Clay, William Henry m. Permelia Stone. (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Clay, William Henry - Amelia County, VA. (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Clay, William Henry - Carroll County, TN. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Clay, William Henry - Clarksville, VA. (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Clay, William Leonard. (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Clay, William Mitchell 1351. (Box 14, Folder 14-19)
    - Clay, William Monroe. (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Clay, William Peyton. (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Clay, William Young. (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Clay, Wilson. (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Clay, Woodson. (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Subseries B. Locality Files., Extent: 7 boxes. (Box 15-21)
    The Locality Files contain much of the same types of information that is found in the Alphabetical Files, but are arranged alphabetically by Virginia county name, followed by other states.
    - Albemarle County. (Box 169, Folder 1)
    - Albemarle County - Loose Papers. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Amelia County. (Box 15, Folder 2-5)
    - Amelia County. (Box 170, Folder 5)
    - Amelia County - Deeds. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Amelia County - Fee Books. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Amelia County - Loose Papers. (Box 15, Folder 8-9)
    - Amelia County - Tax Lists. (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Amelia and Nottoway Counties - Various Lines. (Box 15, Folder 11-12)
    - Augusta County - Tithables. (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Bedford County. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Brunswick County. (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Brunswick County - Loose Papers. (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Buckingham County. (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Campbell County. (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Campbell County. (Box 170, Folder 2)
    - Carroll County. (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Carroll County. (Box 169, Folder 4)
    - Charles City County. (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Charlotte County. (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Chesterfield County. (Box 16, Folder 10-13)
    - Chesterfield County - Tithables. (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Chesterfield County - Tithables. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Cumberland County. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Cumberland County. (Box 170, Folder 7)
    - Cumberland County - Loose Papers. (Box 17, Folder 3-7)
    - Cumberland County - Tithables. (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Dinwiddie County - Loose Papers. (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Franklin County. (Box 17, Folder 10-12)
    - Giles County. (Box 18, Folder 1-3)
    - Gloucester County - 1704 Rent Roll. (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Goochland County. (Box 18, Folder 5-7)